said today
if you notice on the clock webpage
couple things but which one is there's
no link for today
he also knows that i remove the org
lengths for all the previous classes
the files are still there on the web
server following served on
we are switching over to the cure-all
family doing
our updates his burial
so will be asking the server to update
the file for us we don't have to do de
do you get
because we are simply checked them out
ends the other thing to notice here is
we're running out
returned the tools that can help you out
new research in an election when u
about the touch
of what i like to change at the very
small amount and are so many useful
tools
inside of
what could be a research tools or he
could go on for probably three years
one cool thing is that lol brasco
who used to be a full-time research
professor here he is now an affiliate
faculty
for soccer in morse home and he's a part
of the fire
that u_s_ observing and complex systems
group
used to be the lead teacher for
aided in alice escorts who talked about
hard very somewhere goals to what this
class warfare
focus more on specifics
and the are open for packages some
network because quite a bit he's agreed
to come and give you guys over to you
activist repeat careers plus notes and
i myself would like to take its course
i don't know our
at all really i've used are for to come
into my life
but you can actually use are from inside
a pipe bomb
so there's a bridge between the two as
an adult okie why and you can actually
reaching
and use of the school functions from are
inside a python which is pretty neat
anarchism if if the shipper biologist at
super powerful for all those
dealing with this afternoon we have to
crime to statistics to get your answers
and figure out there
so enough of the apple realistic into
are updating
and get started on things
so on the cost data got the notes
i was what we did last time to creep
two projects directory and check out
pouring and uh...
vocabulary of material clone
bill called the party that has all of
our pockets in it
three or three of the first time
once you've got an established this is
the commands
that you can answer will tend to go
update goes
and more
see that the lexington changes pushed
him
beer thing is
before we make those
changes if i can type
that bucket here go back in my history
and to do this
so if we go to the
that bucket site for this there's
actually some nice
tools here so please scroll down for the
research tools project
you can see there's been a budget
changes with them is a message so
the most recent change which was i think
uh... about five minutes ago
i finished a draft for class today
those numbers here are the identifier
for the revision
that iqura vision of the document
they're not very friendly they're
actually i believe andy fibers some
other checked some
so that number uniquely identifies that
change if you click on that wink it'll
actually show you
those changes to your feel like i've
somehow pigs again an old struck the
setup section
sliding brad was removed cream of the
additions
so you can go and see
what's different and if i make changes
between now
and later on if we find mistakes in this
document you can actually see what's
change between when he took
winter sports in here
and when you might be going back to it
so clothes that
doer update
the latest cv in
projects
in here we've got our research tools
directory cecily research
tools
ambled is due
depot command which is going to reach
out
into the place where this was cloned
from and see if there's any updates
and last time we did this there were no
updates said no changes
this time
we expect to see quite a few changes
ignore all the warnings that are coming
from the security certificates
they didn't pay the uh...
because the user charged for having
specially scientific evidence
and you'll see is that adding chains
that sally manifest
adding files trains
added for change that's what's exchanges
to five piles
we don't know that means
you directly care
don't don't worry about it
we go and look in there
so we'll see t_n_t_'s class
if you do ls
we're testing would help
this is weird so this is what happens
when you're needed something any trying
to teach it
i've mostly used it and get that would
totally do the right thing
so when the quick trying to get their
class
if you're in
projects research tools class
type h_d_ space update
and now will see at the very bottom
there is
a twenty-three python binary files part
uh... run update
this is where i should have artsy f_m_'s
you guys remember my definition of arts
yet found
uh... we'll see what happens if we say
debbie t f
artie at film
studio apt to get install w t f very
important for him to have on your
computer
apparently when she doesn't have
the mac actually has to be definitely
tell you we are here from stands for
that a_t_f_
party f_m_
the reality and that will not appear in
arson are screen captures that sits in a
different system
so i want to me is that i will get in
trouble
so now we have our update
now that we know that we need to run
update
even take a look
twenty three so we can do
who could have her email x
control x two
sos open up projects
research tools
klaus
twenty three
so that open that file for projects
rehearsals clocks
twenty-three and python binary files
part
three dot org
here's where it could have my note to
say h_g_ update
in addition to the steeple
so let's go ahead and start following
the setup
from the maker
silicon cd
clear
so i'm glad you are the make their
dash key till the slash class slash
twenty three
careful place to work
cd fills a large class
twenty three
make sure we are rearm
peter t_v_ you can see that
this is the path
for attaining
raped her
you can copy of your file into the local
directory we don't have to
have to do that but it's easier
they can do a copy so far shit
projects
research tools class
twenty three
and what i was frenzy with basically
have you had they were both file on the
same directory effective the day before
that weighs a little bit easier if you
open the files will be in the way
location
so with thirty max that means we need to
control excellent katie kill
artwork file
so it's gone
and then open up
so the slash class slash twenty three
and completely finished
this way
when we start opening files like our
aspect up either will be working on
today
it'll be in the right directors often
start managing directories
members without the other
the result
these if you do see p it'll copy of the
week you copies of the u_n_ and the
because apparently first place
so here we are back at the same file
risk rolled out of the setup
sojourner c_p_
now you guys are gonna run the program
just like before
three if you would have it copy and
because none of that you all the copies
within five years
copy
those joints
and then edit paste over here
and it's gonna run
the curl command to go around the data
file the same one we've been using
lockheed classes
and then be unfair to you
and your sample by aspect are these
interviews
and if you want you can do your mt five
summoned and the extra careful
and thankfully into the same
so now let's start python against
they get back into you by phone
i've papon enrich our and character date
if we can point out our ship track
'cause we're getting close
star-ledger the log start again
so that we don't lose
because we have more power outages
which were on their own for the train
tracks
so long start
dash over dash or log
class
twenty-three doubtfire
presenter
so we've done our log started
if we do know us you'll see there's a
lot of cost twenty three
and now we can import
struct
imports num pate
pronoun p as some people say imports map
family cannot afford it just to make
sure we have it around to work with so
aspect
underscore filed in court for print
sample thought
and will read it carefully have it
around data
file dot read and who wins
the nice thing about actually doing this
is really sweet verified that we can
regard datafile that came in
fifth will be using at a time today
and last time
we did some tweaking to argue max to
make it
uh... highlight
parentheses
so if you see here with my cursor on
semantic it's highlighted both sides
so let's make sure those are turned on
for your
your demat sessions so our tools
turn on
source code parsers semantic
and this is going to help us to be able
to jump to functions faster norco
so make sure you do it
that once those first apartment under
tools
and the other one
is options
karan match highlighting under
so options print match highlighting
tools
so that's now the checkbox next to it
for the few things were options
pre-market
highlight which is the second one down
make sure that checked
and tools
bout six down source code firsters
semantic
if you don't have these options that
it's okay
he just won't have a little fancy
highlighting of but this is going on
now if your lectures davis and i don't
think it's a it's
both of them that this is one of them
under options down at the bottom
their state options
so if you've got a lot of things that
you want to keep them around for next
time you gone
so let's catch up the last time
and rather than typing it all and again
because i think you guys have done not
typing
copy this section so control space at
the first
pounds in the pound bag
will scroll down here to the end of the
source block
it's getting along
so i'm right here
right at the beginning of the pound plus
for the and source
and they do a metadata u_n_ or escape
debian
they'll do a control x to just put the
buffer
control act
control half
to find the file
and will fight aspect top either open up
our
s that part partner
attitude control like the taste
and then we'll save that control x
control s
and what is best ever played
wetpaint ron asked that and see what
happens
and so it should say
starting to run scripts
reading twenty two thousand bites
and then the whole bunch of grammar from
the very first aid graham
you can open up a little
seceded budgets research tools
presenter
h_g_
he he i think
one files updated denouncing the into
your class and twenty three sleep till
two slash
musical dislodged obsessed with three
presenter
now what you can see that you can see p
rerun it so sleepy
those flash projects
against washington arent abt
and and class
flora yet in the twenty three in in town
period
and now a growing feeling that sale
articles
finale granite we seem to have got that
while the dam
and we're ready to start having
kota let's read the whole aspect bio
if we go up to
please click in the top window so we're
now on the aspect by files
go up that i am pipeline hay-three scam
and now hopefully you'll see other
functions
there's decoded main will be adding two
more functions
down uh...
road in the class
who want to go at itgi co two they can
handle
reading any particular packet we like in
the file
so click on decoding
as you take you break the beginning of
the decode function
it dot you can also do a control apts
and search
forty cohen
and keeping control last until that
surround us to back to the response
and the first thing what do you is be
able to sell it that we want to jump to
a particular offset
in the file so if we say deaf
decoded
data karma
offset
and will do it a fault again to be the
first packet
fifty to fifty code
i think a little read you the first
packet
or gary graham out of the file
and then if we look at our unpack
we want to be able to go anywhere in
that data file and grandpa particular
datagram
what we'll do it will take that off that
and why i dont beginning in the and
spots of art
data so are square brackets
for addressing this i will say
offset
plus
zero
it's a little whereas they also plus
zero point sometimes it's good to be a
little bit explicit
you can leave off the plus zero and
still work
and then colon and then offset
plus a time seventeen
so what this is good to you
if we're gonna say offset emma reported
somewhere else in the file and this
action should be seventeen fifty
eight times seventeen
and this is going to be
times
and warren
times speak to you
time seventeen
we'll be right here
physically the third one
so we can do it by changing this number
he can point to file of various offsets
and say we want to start reading here or
here's we're here for somewhere on down
through the file
so in the notes here is that the wine
you'll be doing
and now we also need it creates and
helper functions
and the idea with programming is that
rather jamming everything together into
one giant functional one big file
you want her to break the middle logical
things you can only use
so we have a lot of path that we're
gonna want
to have done for us a lot of times
and one bus passes one of the datagram
size anne do you
keep having to specify a time seventeen
for if you knew that back she was one
hundred thirty six if you were at one
thirty six ever won the file
you try to remember too much
you do a lot of work to recruit a
variable called a different sizes could
have saved
how big
each one of the chunks is so peaceful
section rain here
is one hundred and thirty six bytes long
so put that in our font
output of right above
sodium edta w
control expo
i'm a programmer feel nice
and we also would like to have a
function that ken
tell us
how many datagram we have in the file so
clean off by a life
that we know how long it is here
and we know that each one of these two
hundred and thirty-six bike long
if you take the length of our file
provided by a hundred thirty six
and i have to tell us the number of
datagram veteran that file
assuming the files and
heard somehow close cradle functionality
left for us
so much tighter it slowly
sewed up
num
so now mister storfer number
ta grams
nama nalla documentation strain between
two single quotes
how many
packets are and data
really does the commons for now
in the first thing to do is asserts
something
so is it what assert does
is if
you put in expression a written resolves
to true or false
straight-out if you say asserts
zero equals zero
it it's ok but what's a start
that one equals zero
so that one and zero are the same thing
uh... it doesn't think that's true
and so it throws an error saying
i really don't think we've that one
equals zero
i'm gonna give up and quit
so what you can do inside a dirt road is
when you know something should be true
but it's always possible coming to be
broken
you'd like to check it before you go on
because
being really really bad and confusing if
he didn't check it person
it's messed up with the files or online
if something strong cater that jump in
the file
you'd like to know
right away rather than getting part with
your code somewhere else in discovering
that
from is not working and you can figure
out that the files the wrong link and
probably not nafta
suppose there for the third that might
be able to use your ticket sister true
and nothing happens it keeps going if
you see a search
false
it blows up and says five
something's wrong frankly
so we can add assert
ellie and of data so the length of our
data
there's a section
here says percent or modern m_ o_ d_
so the person symbol
cardinal ahmad stands for either
since that sort of we're vocabulary but
what that is is
if you divide something
so please say
twenty-one divided by
is five
that uh... the number four is that are
in twenty one but if we say percent
asked the remainder lied to you in your
division
for them on
characters actually really helpful
sometimes they can do some really
powerful treks
so see some examples of these days zero
maude to you
will get back nothing because the rope
remain your dear to my bike you with us
if we have one divided by two we have a
remainder of one
and we get one
too divided by two
is going to be deleted that divides in
the remainder
presenter there's no remainder
and three
maude to you
gives us
so what do you think's going to happen
if we have one hundred
maude five
what's going to be one hundred and four
mob five
so what this does this tell you
if you know what the packet size that's
gonna be the same always go to file if
you divide the packet size in the file
like can you get any remainder
something's really wrong
you getting a partial packet somewhere
in there
for the file isn't even an aspect
for this asserting our current
a certain length of data
maude datagram size so with the
remainder
for assert that that's
equal to zero with double equals
and as long as there's no remainder
that's true and colby planning
so if we pass a bad file this is going
to
possibly attack that is the wrong one
and refund checks is pretty simple
we wanted know how many do you think
there are so we return
the length of data
divided by the datagram size
that'll be one thirty six
as defined right up above
since they've got
control x control us
and let's go ahead and give it a try
so first
i don't believe
motorist that so if we say import
agreed to import aspect first
for the first time in from now on the
canoe reload
thought to be safe india preload asked
that
now we can't test it with our data so we
can say length
aspect
data
we get back twenty two thousand seven
hundred and twelve
let's try dividing up by one thirty six
does do it ourselves
we get there there's a hundred and sixty
seven packets
now let's try it
too too
seven one sees or total length
maude and then our packet length which
is
one hundred and thirty six points
three did zero
so they should be ok
so let's go ahead and try from asked
that are numb datagram so ask that
nam
underscored it data grams
el paso tar aspect
data
we should get back
a hundred and sixty seven datagram in
our file
and lo and behold at work
if you have an indentation air online
twenty one
that means he shoots chlorophyll your or
twenty-four the consul one
press pound
and i'll read emphatically no bump it
back one
scroll down to more returned
and first-half again and i will reinvent
outline
and then you can say with control x
controller
right
kenny g_ certainly the country's
diseases visited and sizes pacific two
aspects
with an afterthought everything of
immigrants the same size
we can't change that is fixed
by the people who died designed bs that
format
so we're stuck with a hundred and thirty
six by splitting graham
uh... there are other formats with all
sorts of other sizes and shapes and
strangeness
so now we have a function that if we
ever want to know
how many different era file you can just
ask if you will tell you
just a warning
for the rest the coach today i'm not
writing force feed stucco time writing
will be kind of slow
so if you actually start doing aspect
processing and you want to use a eight
hundred megabyte file
you want to talk to me or call and or
someone who's done this before
hand-written code to go fast because the
school and really slow on the files
but at least it will show you the basics
of how to do it
okay so the other thing would like to do
is
for each day to crammed into one of the
kids some phoenix a datagram number
fifty
we want to know how far in the file it
is
and that's actually fairly easy to
figure out you take the datagram number
anymore fired by the datagram size and
that should give you
the number of where we are so if we have
one thirty six is our datagram size
and we multiply that by
that fifty eight datagram
is that
location six thousand eight hundred
now we could just do that anymore
because we need it but that's not very
nice thoughts create a function that
will capture that
process of getting the offset
serve right below your death num data
grams
but at a function called death
underscore offset
and a pass at the datagram number
that porn
no have a documentation string u can
skip this if you want
calculates
uh... starting
offset uh... datagram
dated graham
number
you're
so i'm counting from zero here
the first in a gram is not number one
as the number zero
and will save return
data
grandma underscore number
finance
datagram
underscore size
those functions apart very big or
exciting but this way
you when you read the code
you understand what the person is trying
to do get the offset for our family
datagram czar
rather than seeing some number of times
one thirty six or some number divided by
one thirty six
and hopefully it will make your code a
lot more understandable
so let's try it
full-fare reload
and i will try doing some offset so
aspect
but get underscore
metab
offset
fewer things that down the road you
wanna put in what's called unit tests
do you want to capture of these things
because you know the answer
if your code ever stop producing the
right answer
then it's probably broken
and there's nothing like
fayette cap walking across your keyboard
when you're coming
and maybe try to undo what's in their
um... unfortunate real stories
so what you do with the things that you
build up with color unit tests and won't
make it to your intestines class but
they're they're very important for
scientific data pricing
we knew the first one was supposed to be
at position zero
and in fact is that this is a real quick
work of
we do an offset of one
which in a return to us
a hundred and thirty-six exactly
and if we try expect our debt
offset
a hundred and twenty-five this is where
i wouldn't know off of my head
with the number would be
it's at seventeen thousand
or we can do the fifty that we did
before
sources to that
so fifty should be a six thousand eight
hundred natives
so that we have some helper functions
that are gonna make ur life polite user
rating cohen
for the rest of it
and we're going to come on if i remain
to start being a lot more useful
so if you could any respect up high
final
any go to your granddad fight on
scrawled on the functions
you'll see there's now to actor
functions monday two grams and get off
that
for what it's like name
and go down to the main function
this way
if i might be able to receive within
your file not happen
keep remembering
is the main down below are proper or
somewhere in the middle
click on that insecure main
family can start modifying it
if you start your main file with the
printed read this many bites
parental leave everything in the main
from there on down
through god
sarmistha highlight that region
from print to print
press control w
to cut it
from our main only has three line for
the prints
and every year the data
so there's none
a common heres his new code starts here
in the notes that for start
tools are oppressing print
and rather than love
the file line but that isn't terribly
interesting to see prints number of
data grams
colin inside of a string
comox and then we can use their function
to calculate the number of datagram
sonam underscore
gary graham's
and i'll pass it are asked that
underscored data
what what do you know
if you're going to want to walk through
that data file
for each packet we know how many package
there are political operative or packets
and after above location each one
political parties that data using art
deco
so will for start off by creating a
little pattern that's going on
what would pronounce so
print administering updated graham
number comma time
from our x caramel one
this is going to give us a little after
information
and now we're gonna go to a for a loop
it's gonna luv overall the number of
data grams so four
catering and index
that's going to be very well that
contains the number of our datagram
range
so great is going to return us the
sequence of numbers
between zero and i finally get it
they're not including the highest number
and we want a passive is the number of
datagram ceramic count from
zero through
i think we've
a hundred twenty six nanograms
no one type in the number one to ask
it's a nam
deliverance
aspect underscore data
sludge return a hundred and twenty six
a colon to end the definition before
loop
and inside
find out what the offsets going to be so
offset equals
offset
datagram index
so first time through that's going to be
zero
and look at the outset zero two zero
for the country for anyone
get off that would turn
a hundred and
uh... thirty six
so then what we need to do is use art
deco
without offset to go into that
blocks of data and grab a red one
returns the dictionary
sourcing peter graham equals decode
memoranda passive first today don't
suspect underscored data
comma
and then that possibly just calculate
offset
now we could print the whole dictionary
in without
getting kind of annoying
source a prince
and we use the datagram index
there we're there's a part of our
four-wheel so
welfare which number one
animals gokhale at the time
fortitude in degrees in life in degrees
so will say datagram underscore index
comma
datagram
slots are dictionary came back
the first on this time
the remember this uh... definition
of what's where
so that i grabbed out of time
the datagram
hello and underscore
to green
candidate gramm
quality and for the green
go ahead and say that and we'll see how
well it's hard to see if we have any
bugs
source format cells
reload
now here i just on the right in the make
life easier
since we've modified our main so we can
just say we're on
and hopefully
what's gonna happen is a whole lot of
stuff has been a guest you mean across
your screen at the hundred and to the
island twenty six lines
fossil hatter
cement enter encinitas you mean by it
and what they're up we've got lots of
data
so if you have now as a nice little
table
where this ship was way collected the
sticker dataset
here we did our ryan
and now we have are
results
and we have a hundred sixty seven of
them
that's great unfortunately it's spread
out on the screen and we can really use
that result anywhere
so we need to improve our code
and what would like to do with people to
you have something that we could
across this
and every time through return factor
next datagram
in python they have something called
generators and this is going to be a lot
like magic
it's kind of strange
if you get used to generators and you
have lots of data formats
creating a generator for each one means
you can write up for
something rather in some file
every country that poor loop it's gonna
return you the next item from that file
really really powerful and really really
compact so it's only a couple lines of
code
if you don't really understand every now
just try to absorb it and when you get
the running one of your own go back and
read a python documentation answered
tutorials on generators
and me come back a look at this
if you need more help on that ask away
and all trying to be a better
description uh... generators
of convert that into a generator inside
of our current
min ago just about names
create a function that
basically
it's going to low tar file and give it
back
one expected gramm at that time
creer function names the load underscore
aspect underscore final
el paso the file name
unicorn
cuter documentation strengths of this is
aid
iro generator in all caps so that you
would recognized the word since that's
what you would start on
in that condition
can with
over
with days
and will do the same thing we did before
recovering a file
instead of opening
a specific file to get here
we're going to open up file name welfare
asked that
file equals open
file name so hopefully passing that
ended
aspect
data equals as pat underscore file
thought
lead
so it's very similar we did before
and now we're gonna whip across all of
those lineages special function aldy
yield
and yield is what's gonna return back
are
next is a gram
and will try to sell an animal good try
out some of us to see what it's like
sold for
datagram
underscore index
in range
nam underscored a difference
aspect underscored data that's gonna
return
are hundred and sixty seven
will view are offset equals get
underscore offset
datagram underscore index
so it's gonna return zero for the first
one
one hundred exists for the second one
and so on
datagram equals
decode
aspect
data
come off offset
now if you're having trouble keeping up
with the typing or if you're having
typing akruti troubles you can also
smith
faith in the section because to have
can go back through later
i'm also want to add in the index number
so before we kept track of it
i'd like to the datagram
dictionary to also have this index
number
so we need to add to our dictionary
subsurface next thing is going to be for
safety there
fram
left square brackets unquote index
rating will quote right square bracket
people feeling cramped
index
that way we know which datagram were on
and then this is the magical
generator thing receipt yields
datagram
will say that
we now have this magical functions
will live through our files return back
to us one dictionary
that contains
and asked that activity
so let's try this by hand before putting
it
and a four week so you can see what's
going on a little bit
still hard to understand this way but at
least you'll have a sense of that's
creating some special objects
soldiers will do our reload about
spectacle rav our new york
now it is a sample
equals
aspect dot load
underscore
aspect underscore file
and now we have to pass in a file name
because we have engineer function the
doesn't know which files being opened
for example
aspect
if we take type
sample
it says
i've got a generator
took a lot different than used to seeing
you think that returns as an actual
dictionary
these generators
that kind of papon and not that many
people are familiar with them
but it really is
a wonderful too lol if you can get
comfortable with it
so if we say prince
sample
it shows us that the generator
objects
and then says it's a load of aspect
files
commanders formal where member
so tocqueville about working from the
list of chinese itself
the yield in their triggered this weird
generator creation
at ono help i point out that kind of
baffles me in some ways of looking at
how they magically definitely for your
kind of function
rather than being a role function turns
in the center
so we can do now is said
sample period and then tab
and that's the completion that shows us
what's in there
captain and i don't know what a lot of
these things do but there's a key one in
here
next
sat next to function call is what's
gonna get a factor datagram so-called
sample but
next
to print the seems express answer
we actually get back
idea graham
so it's kinda cool
is it not braille ba ba convince him to
a very well they can't do anything with
so we can save data
graham
equals
sample thought
next
and it's kind of a fun
she could have been shown you and i
python defied team
york type out the word print
because i think the authors of i fight
on bart blessed typing the better
so use print
datagram
and we have
our dictionary
that contains one datagram if we look
somewhere in here should be added to
grant index
for our index is one
now if we do know datagram
and we printed out
source second one our index is now too
so if we keep asking it for another next
next next next will be able to walk
through the whole dataset
stinky calling
fairport dot next
and simple but next sample dot next to
the nearest the velocities here
being yourself
if you want those they keep changing
so if you watch that number the next
time through
it's a little bit different
saurabh grabbing each of the different
packets back from the file
now if you have to go it is for some of
the data format expected to take your
while to represent all around
it's really fifteen
twenty-fifth
so let's try and do it here for a living
so you can say for sample in aspect dot
loaded
asked that
and then to give it the same polka
aspect
name of the farm
cohen three or four we're going to walk
over every single day two grams file
and thankfully this is a simple period
pilots mall
press answer
and now it's just print out the sample
that comes through east timor forward so
it's going to return
carter does your four with the primitive
is back at sample within the u
determinant
breast cancer
three times
siphon types is gonna fill your screen
for
of data grams in a very not useful life
close to organize your rent
so it's replaced are printed just simple
with simple
square brackets imo
cooper wants to
discord agrees
form of sample
square brackets black
degrees
so let's try that command press enter
three times
and you should hopefully see some of the
lot nicer
where you actually get
the longitudinal ivc printing out into
columns all the way down to my head
enter
enter enter
and now we have
are creek track
in some of us looking like we might
actually be able to plop that's pretty
soon with matt hotlines
it would be much better if we say this
to a variable for the kids do something
with it because
i'd like you but i'm not going to get
out some graph paper and point out those
thoughts on the map somewhere in the
chart and then go looking for those
numbers assistant fawn
four state eighteen twelve
helped create empty list
beverly hill loop through it and we're
gonna add
stuff to you this week the farm so we
had to be able to work with
would create are blank list will say
four
sample in
i'm gonna go pat go on because i don't
like typing so much
so this one is the same the first one in
the prints line
minute control katie killed that
so just like he max control k
kills firmware perjury is to the very
end
will safety that thought
and then i'll
what purpose even a right parentheses
inside of that append we're gonna pass a
little
list
city square brackets
so inside of this
for a profit first the sample
wanted to
not log but long
to greens
and our sample
degrees
so you've got that go ahead and answer
to help with this actually works
anyone
death nothing
so instead of printing it out we've
actually saving the variable so we don't
have to face down
on the data
remember the whose commands
we can say coolers and left them for
their return to us the worst taipei
rebels
and i have one of those wheeler-dealer
agency that we have
entries with court incidence
turn it up to four harvest season
conceded at
zero get back our first one
we have an accent wine
who want to see the last one
data square brackets minus one
ship with driving a straight line
this will be our bounding box
but if we can make it to the plot you'll
see the ship with that we not driving
straight line
that's okay but
it might be better to have
a dictionary or
like that but why don't we
i need it was
rebuild the data
so that it's actually
dictionaries
and each one of those entries we've got
all the values and come back through
them
so for anyone baby equals left
rebecca rates were bracket
ferrer wiped out they absolutely do
whose lists
we have an empty list for datum
and we'll say four
sample
detected old stuff
data append
and then it just
correct for square bracket control cable
need everything for the end
and with this type sample
so we just want
alleged that's got a dictionary for
every one of our data grams
if you were doing an eight hundred make
about file your machine but basically
lockup at this point
but for this time it's not too bad
enter
three times
redone type whose west
and you can now sears curly braces in
here with a name
so we can go
and get things by name so we can save
data
grab the firstborn
and then we can say
long
report green
and we get back to our degrees
so what we wanted to know that we can
build the worst of all of our acts as a
list of all of our life
and then with the plot
so it's create a list of our taxes
so x underscore left
and i'm giving it not just the name tax
because
want to create new ray an umpire a later
on
to distinguish the two
summoned nick an explicit just sort of a
temporary lest nirmal turned into
so will say that is an empty list
with she square brackets
now we can say four
sample and data
and we can say acts list
apparent
and in their we're gonna pass it sample
long
greens
sold to his boat a list of just the axis
press ctrl
and enter center
let's runner who was again
too so we can see it
and now we have a list his chest are
accidents
and for speed was turned into an array
so i think we worried unimportant on
private for that
all the notes
ama se exit polls num high-end dot array
democrats of our list
except for a list
so now if we do
p search
if you haven't seen before
this is a cert on variables
it kinda like whose but it searching on
the very romanian their memory
it should return all of our
very well for the named
we have an axe
annex lists
and we have a function called x_-wing
stuck in there
type who's
enteral finex in here
annual creature was in a rain
spectrum rhode island and erase refuse
andy arranged
and we'll see that it's a hundred
sixty-seven elements an suv type float
let's go ahead and bought it we need not
followed
bought
would imports
hyatt block
with her daughter interactive motor we
don't have to fill too much
buy a plot
interactive
true
wat
so this is gonna start seeing our crews
track
for our ship
and there we go
this is a ship
this is the x
axes of where they were in terms of
wanted to to their youth west location
and they went out
and that kind of came back a little bit
and outgoing back cannot backed him then
well confusing justin one dimension
let's go ahead and try to do the same
exact thing we do it acts with flying
feminists roll up to my
through my list here in the first thing
we want to do
was create an axe underscore listless
conductor y underscore list
skin and we'll go back up a grab our for
loop
como edit it
so before three or four simple and data
now we have excellence solutions that
help wireless
and we had simple memory access
hello landowners order green ones that
access provided to you
or l_a_ teams are applied
presenter twice three times
now we want to convert that
soapy type out the news
list will see that we now have a
wireless
right there was convert that to iran
so will say why equals
known by
animals there were a
its habitat at that time
mci messing
wireless
breast cancer
and now we typed
andy array
we now have our acts in a y arrays of
the comply
now we are do you have something in here
if we try to pop the white the same time
all this show you a does bad things
subpart plot
again we get to plots that are not
really related so
we have our x and y a very different
locations that are plot terrible
and in the notes there's a nice solution
for that repair
pipe ought dot c l_ a_
which will clear
for ground
hi plot c l_ a_
fantasies that cleared are grappling our
staffing in there
or just plotter wine sabbatical quite
before we
jump into anything else and the white
and has the same
really missed a lot very helpful
understand what the ship was doing
so it's run another c l_ a_ will get rid
of that
that's gone
you know it's a pie
x comma why so this is going to fought
it sort of a map you look
and
there's no ships
this is their careers track for this
aspect file
so this is not mowing the lawn
they're doing something different
so unfortunately we didn't get a normal
survey which would be nice to sort of
see
typical monologue that comes with had
rafiq serving
but it's still pretty interesting so we
now know what the ship was doing in
terms of their location
and for now digging into that data and
were actually able to read into this
binary aspect that the first looked like
fine a repeal
went to get at this and if the format
will describe you can offer them a
couple hours right aforeserve for that
data
working with within sight of it
so i'm gonna and free here will pick up
on next class with trying to build a
came out
this uh...
testbed final and then we'll move on
to glaspie complex lost couple classes
and binary files if you have done it
before it happened to be confusing
if he didn't get off
directorate
and ask some questions that evening
expected to take some time before you
understand fully
so a lot of stuff
commensurate with